Usman Zaver

Lahore, 54000, Pakistan • +923075959036 • <u>usmanzaver@gmail.com</u> • <u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>Portfolio</u>

Summary

As a Unity Game Developer, I bring over 2.5 years of industry experience in developing and releasing video games. With a strong educational foundation in Computer Science, I am enthusiastic about driving innovation in video games on all platforms, with a particular focus on mobile gaming. I have successfully created and launched more than 10 products on the Google Play Store having a player base of millions.

Experience

GeniTeam Solutions

Lahore, Pakistan

Mobile game developer and publisher, known for Scary Teacher 3D. Software Engineer

Oct 2020 – Current

- Developed and launched 10+ mobile games on Google Play Store.
- Integrated various SDKs, including GameAnalytics, Firebase, Google AdMob, and other MMP tools to enhance game monetization and user data acquisition.
- Leveraged data analytics and A/B testing to optimize game mechanics, resulting in a 10% increase in player retention.
- Utilized analytics to enhance player progression and increase ad impressions per user, driving revenue growth.
- Reduced the downloadable size of products by 30% using Asset Bundles along with Play Asset Delivery.
- Significantly improved game performance by expertly using the Unity profiler and applying various optimization techniques.

Arbisoft Lahore, Pakistan

Innovative software development company specializing in web and mobile apps. Software Engineer Intern

Jul 2019 – Aug 2019

- Learned industry level coding standards for Python.
- Developed Web Scraper using Scrapy.
- Developed restaurant review site using Diango.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Information Technology University

CGPA: 3.04

2016 - 2020 Pakistan

Other

- **Technical Skills:** C#, Unity, Git, Smart SVN, Game Optimization, Game Design, Game Analysis, Prototyping, Asset Bundles, Physics, Object Oriented Programming
- Languages: English (Fluent), Urdu (Native)